Hello everyone, today we are going to learn how to make a butterfly knot in Marvel's The Santa
First, we need to open this dress in the preview and put it on any virtual model
In the attribute editor, reduce the surface diameter of the virtual model to 1
Make the clothes closer to the virtual model
Select all dress panels, reduce their particle diameter to 10
Then copy it with the control key
Here we reduce the particle diameter in advance to prevent the butterfly knot and the smaller panel from merging
There may be unstable problems
Then we freeze all the dress panels and start to make the butterfly knot
First we make a rectangle
This rectangle is the ear of the butterfly knot we will make later
Then select this panel to apply new fabric
Then merge the rectangular side to the front and middle of the collar
Here we can switch to the line knot tool by pressing the shortcut key N
Merge the same side of the line
Because these two panels are folded
We need to switch the type of knot of this set of knots to Turned
Then simulate by pressing the control key
After opening the simulation, we can manually drag this pattern around.
Then we can manually drag this pattern around.
Again, we can manually drag this pattern around.
And press W to click on the pattern to create a fixed needle
Use the fixed needle to flat it in the three-dimensional space
Then the particle diameter of the ear of the butterfly knot will be reduced to 10
The conflict thickness will be reduced to 1
If you want to delete the fixed needle, press W to click again to delete
But if it is not fixed, the pattern will collapse gently
It's not very convenient for us to make the following
It's not very convenient for us to make the following work.
Let's take a look at the shape of the rectangle created in my video
You can see its specific length when you use the edit sheet tool to select one edge
Because the butterfly knot is going to be two layers later
This layer of butterfly knot belongs to the inside
So we need to turn this sheet over on the surface
Because the sheet is now facing the back
Then we need to click on the outer edge of it in 3D space
Then find this line in the corresponding position in the 2D window
Choose to open this sheet
Now we have the outside of the butterfly knot
Just create a line in the middle to fold
Then go to 3D space
Use the fold arrangement tool to select this inner line
Then drag the arrow on the corresponding side to fold the sheet over
After folding, press the control grid button to open the simulation
Now the butterfly knot material is relatively soft
The butterfly knot material is relatively soft
And the ears are lower
We can first harden the sheet to fold
After starting the simulation
You can see the hardened sheet
Its folding effect is very obvious
And the sheet itself has a certain support
Then we step on the particle precision of the butterfly knot to 5
To get better simulation effects
Then we press the shutter button to switch to the line division tool
Connect the two sides of this butterfly knot
Since the lines on both sides are also folded, we need to switch the line type to Turned.
Now we have finished sewing the butterfly knot, we can simulate it.
After folding the board and sewing it, we can remove the hardening.
Don't let the board keep hardening.
To prevent the butterfly knot from falling, we can press the W key and click the corner of the butterfly knot board.
Add a fixing pin at the corner position.
Then, in order to make it easier for us to make the knot of the butterfly knot later, we need to activate the collar board and simulate it together.
In order to make the board more stable, we reduce the particle diameter to 5 and the conflict thickness to 1.
Then continue to simulate it with the control key.
Then, in order to make the butterfly knot look more real, we need to draw some internal lines in the middle and set the folding angle to fold the middle.
Use the internal multidirectional line tool to draw a foldable internal line.
Refer to the position of the internal line in the 3D window.
We move this internal line down a little bit.
Then right-click when CTRL-C and CTRL-V.
You can set the root number of the copyed internal line and the interval between them.
After the three internal lines are created, use the foldable ruler tool.
Click the top of the first internal line.
Double-click the bottom of the last internal line.
Then select the type of winder.
You can see that after selecting the winder, our internal line row is one red, one green, one outward, one inward, and one outward.
When we start the simulation, you can see that this board will be folded along the position of the internal line.
Then you can use the editing board tool to choose the top points of these internal lines.
Extending the internal line can make its folding effect more obvious.
If you see that there are some shaking or unstable places during the simulation,
you can try to reduce the particle diameter of the board a little bit.
Now we are making a butterfly knot with an opening.
If we need to make a butterfly knot with the upper and lower seams,
we can use the line tool to sew the upper and lower seams together.
Here, we use the line tool, the mouse is relative, to click twice.
You can also choose to use the line tool in the 3D window to sew.
But in this position, we don't need it to be flattened,
so we don't need to change the type of internal line.
Then press Ctrl-Z to return to the time when the internal line has not been created yet.
Then use the adjustment board tool to select this board.
Then press Ctrl-D to create a symmetrical board.
Since there is a symmetrical relationship between the boards,
the internal line will also move automatically.
Including the fixing pins on the board will also be created.
Here I don't recommend you to cancel the fixing pins now,
because we haven't hit the knot in the middle yet.
If we cancel the fixing pins, the board will fall down,
and it will affect our future location of the knot creation.
Press Ctrl-Z to return to the time when the fixing pins were still added.
Then we need to add another layer outside this butterfly knot,
so press Ctrl-C, Ctrl-V,
to paste a new butterfly knot.
Because later we may adjust the width of this butterfly knot,
so we delete the fixing pins first,
press W to click to cancel the fixing pins,
then press W to create two fixing pins in the inner position.
Although in the early stage,
we have already determined the size of the butterfly knot
during the process of creating the butterfly knot,
but if we want to modify the board later,
it is also possible.
As in my video,
we can move the upper and lower sides of the whole first,
to shorten the width of the entire butterfly knot.
If we want to modify the length of this butterfly knot,
we first move the side near the inner side,
and move the inner line used for folding.
The side used for sewing and folding,
we will not move it.
Then press Ctrl-Z to start the simulation.
You can see that there is no sewing line in the middle,
so we need to manually sew these two boards together.
Here we use the line sewing tool to sew the two sides together.
After sewing,
because they are combined,
so we don't need to modify their sewing line type.
Then you can delete these two fixing pins,
and then add two fixing pins to the fold position,
and then press Ctrl-Z to start the simulation.
This butterfly knot is like being flattened.
Then we can refer to the butterfly knot position on the picture,
use the free sewing tool to fix part of the outer butterfly knot
to the inner butterfly knot.
When creating the sewing line,
it reminds us that we have folded the sewing line,
so we need to remove the connection of one of the butterfly knots.
Then select the free sewing tool,
first select the outer butterfly knot,
and then select the line of the bottom butterfly knot to the inside,
and then select the line of the bottom butterfly knot to the outside,
and then the sewing line type is changed to Turned.
When processing this kind of multi-layer cloth,
we need to create the sewing line in the same position,
we try to let the two layers together,
do not cross-layer to sew,
this is easy to be unstable.
Then we put together with the butterfly knot,
the example of the collar half piece is reduced a little bit,
to make it more stable.
Then press the W key,
on the bottom of the butterfly knot,
add two pins,
press the Shift key,
you can select more pins.
When opening the simulation,
click and drag the pin,
so that there is enough space between the butterfly knot and the body,
it is convenient for us to wear the knot board later.
Then check the effect of the butterfly knot,
the butterfly knot on the top may still be a little bigger,
so we repeat the steps before.
First of all, we will not repeat the steps before,
now it will not be affected by the adjustment board,
add two pins to the position,
and then delete the excess pins.
Then you can use the editing board tool,
to drag the top of the butterfly knot board,
and then shorten the width of this board,
because the symmetry relationship has been cancelled,
so after we have modified one side,
the top of the other side also needs to be moved.
Because there are many sewing lines on the butterfly knot board,
as well as internal lines and pins,
so we will not use the adjustment board tool
to completely shrink the butterfly knot,
but to modify one side by one side.
Then we will start to fold the middle part of the butterfly knot,
first we need to press the W key,
click on the middle part of the butterfly knot,
create a few pins,
then in the state of opening the simulation,
drag these pins,
and drag the material out while modeling.
Because if we go directly to the knot in the middle,
the middle knot part,
its fold may be outward,
or inward,
so we have to fold the top of the butterfly knot
to the back before adding the knot.
Now let's turn the view
to a slightly sideways view,
then press the W key,
click on the top of the butterfly knot,
and the middle position,
then in the state of opening the simulation,
drag the pin,
let the top position of the butterfly knot
fold backwards,
then press the W key to hide the virtual model,
then you can continue to adjust the pin to the right position.
Of course,
you can also adjust the other positions of the pin according to your needs.
Then the inner line of the fold position can be deleted.
After a short simulation,
you can press the W key to display the virtual model.
Then we can put these two
fixed pins together,
and we can delete them.
The same operation method,
press the W key,
click on these two fixed pins,
and you can delete them.
Then we can select all the butterfly knot ear pieces,
and then freeze them.
Next, let's do the knot.
First of all,
we have to make a rectangular piece
in the 2D window.
Its length is almost twice the width of the butterfly knot.
Here you can refer to
the rectangular size I made in the video.
Then we have to turn this knot into a ring,
and then put it outside the butterfly knot.
Now we first press the W key,
click on this knot piece,
and fix it in the 3D space.
Then reduce its particle diameter to 3,
and reduce the overlap thickness to 1.
Because later this knot piece
will be placed outside the butterfly knot,
so its particle diameter is relatively low.
Then we have to draw a line in the middle
with the inner line to fold.
Because if we don't fold first,
we can't sew it directly.
If we don't fold first,
after it starts to model,
it may overlap by itself.
So we need to fold this knot piece first.
This way we can ensure that
it won't overlap after sewing.
We use the folding arrangement tool first,
and then choose a side to turn it over.
Then press the W key to start modeling,
and wait for them to be simulated.
Now when they are sewn well
and form a structure similar to a ring,
we can delete the inner line.
Then we press the W key to simulate,
and let it form a round ring.
Then we can see that
when this ring is directly
covered outside the butterfly knot,
it can't be covered.
Because now the butterfly knot is frozen,
and there are many layers,
it is not very convenient
for us to wear it directly.
So we put this knot piece
and pull it out.
Then here,
we can use the shrink to
turn it into a bigger ring.
When we choose the editing logic tool,
and choose a sheet,
we can see the line direction
on this sheet.
Since we want to stretch this sheet,
we should modify the golden shrink.
After we start the simulation,
we can see that this sheet
is now twice as long as the original.
Then we can pause the simulation,
drag this sheet to the virtual model
and put it between the virtual model and the butterfly knot.
When we start the simulation,
the virtual model will automatically
take this sheet out,
so that this sheet
will pass through the butterfly knot.
Then we delete the fixed needle
used to fix the knot,
and activate the butterfly knot ear plate
and simulate this knot together.
Now this butterfly knot,
its balance position is outside.
We need to hide the virtual model,
drag the sheet,
and drag this balance to the inside.
Because the virtual model is hidden,
we can now rotate to the back view,
drag this knot piece little by little,
so that its balance position
is hidden in a place that cannot be seen.
After that,
we can delete these fixed needles
used to fix the knot.
It's still the same operation.
Press the W key,
click on the fixed needle that has been created,
and you can delete these fixed needles.
Now open the simulation by pressing the W key.
The butterfly knot ear plate
will return to the original virtual model
when it was attached.
And our knot plate
has passed through the butterfly knot ear plate.
Next, we will return the shrink rate
to the normal ratio.
When reducing the shrink rate,
it should be considered that
because the plate is not increased now,
but reduced,
when we reduce it,
please do not reduce it too much.
You can start from 200 to 150,
then 120,
then 100,
and so on.
Because the knot is not tight now,
we need to adjust its length manually.
First of all,
we can use the editor tool
to move its bottom
to shorten the length of this knot.
But be careful,
when moving this line,
do not move too much at a time.
We can refer to the seam line
in the 3D window.
Try not to cross this seam line
with other panels,
otherwise it may be unstable
or pierced.
In addition,
we put this seam line
to the flat position
at the back of the piece
in advance
to make it easier
for us to shorten its length.
In the video,
I also made a mistake demonstration.
Here,
I made its panel
too short at once,
resulting in the seam line
and other places
have a gap,
so it cannot be well wrapped
around the collar panel.
We press ctrl z
to return to the normal simulation
before.
When we usually
modify this knot panel,
on the one hand,
we should pay attention
to modify its length
as much as possible
and add it
several times.
On the other hand,
if we want to
not modify the panel
in advance
and tighten it,
we need to
reduce the shrink rate
to a value
that is even smaller
than the original 100,
for example,
80.
Now we can see
that the knot panel
is tightened tightly.
After selecting the knot panel,
press shift q
to hide the knot panel.
We can delete
the extra pins.
At the same time,
press shift w
to remove the extra pins.
Now,
we can see
that the knot panel
is tightened tightly.
Press shift w
to show all the panels.
If we need to tighten
the knot panel
tighter,
we can
reduce the shrink rate
a little bit.
However,
we need to pay attention
that when we use
the shrink rate
for a panel,
in fact,
its grid
is also reduced
by the same amount.
In other words,
we need to pay attention
to the movement
of this place
when we modify the material.
Next,
we can remove
the fixing pin
and make
the following adjustments.
If we want to
delete
all the fixing pins,
we can use
the move tool
to select
a fixing pin
and then right-click
to delete
all the fixing pins.
After deleting
all the fixing pins,
we can see
that the panel
is now
tightened.
When the butterfly knot
is in the current
shape,
if we want
to change the panel
again,
because there are some
knot panels
and the function
of the seam line
may cause
instability,
we can also
use the shrink rate
to adjust
the shape
of the panel.
Now we can see
that the fold
of the inner line
is a bit out of place,
but we can't
adjust the inner line
directly now.
Let's take a look
here.
If I adjust
the inner line
to the
horizontal position
and can't see
the fold position,
once we
start the simulation,
the whole panel
will return
to its natural
simulation effect.
The effect of the inner line
will no longer be retained,
so we must
make sure that
the current
shape of the panel
is OK.
Finally,
we delete the inner line
before the fold.
Next,
we can adjust
the shape
of the butterfly knot.
First of all,
we can adjust
the shape
of the butterfly knot
by adding a fixing needle
and moving the fixing needle
to make the butterfly knot
stand up.
We can also
control the shape
of the butterfly knot
through physical properties.
Select the
butterfly knot fabric
and then
increase the bending
strength
of the physical property
in the editor
. The higher the bending
strength,
the thicker the fabric
will look.
Next,
we can increase
the bending strength
and the strength
of the folding line
of the panel.
When these values
are increased,
the fabric will not
stretch easily,
and the support
of the fabric
will become stronger,
and it will also
look harder.
And because it is
harder to stretch,
it can
have more
wrinkles.
When we
modify these properties,
we can start
the simulation
and wait
for the panel
to come out.
In order to
make the butterfly knot
panel
have a better
simulation effect,
we can also
reduce the
particle strength
of these panels.
Reducing
the particle strength
also helps
us to
have a more
round effect
after
deleting
the inner line
later.
Finally,
we can
delete the inner line
and then
we can
double-check
several times
to get a better
result.
Next,
let's go back
to the time
when the inner line
has not been deleted
before.
Let's
freeze the
butterfly knot panel
first.
Let's optimize
the knot in the middle.
Now the knot
is just a
flat
single
knot.
First,
let's reduce
the tail-line
of the knot panel
a little,
such as
80%
to 80%.
After
the simulation
is started,
the knot panel
will become
narrower.
Then we can
use the
fixing needle
to fix
the lines
on both sides.
In the tool
selection
of the grid
tool,
find the
fixing needle
comparison tool.
Then go to
the 2D window
and add a
fixing needle
along
the edge
of the grid
with
double-check
on the
line.
If it is too obvious,
we can
return it
to 90
here.
The fixing needle
on both sides
cannot be deleted
because once
we delete
the fixing needle,
it will return to
the original
simulation effect.
Next,
let's
solve all
the butterfly knot
panel
panels
and simulate them
together.
Next,
let's learn
how to make
cross knots.
Let's go back
to the previous
example.
Draw
a middle line
of this panel
with
a pink guide line.
Then,
use the tool
right-click
to select
cut.
Then we simulate
it.
Then we can
appropriately
pull these two panels
together a little wider.
Then,
as before,
reduce
the end
of these two panels
a little bit.
Then
we
need to
merge
these two panels
together.
Before merging,
we need to
replace
their
lines.
Press the
shortcut key
N
to switch to
the
editor
line tool.
Select
the line
at the top of
us,
delete
them,
and maintain
the same
cross
knot.
After opening the
simulation,
because now
we are
mixing
knots behind
us,
we can
see
that
the
two panels
are
the same.
Then,
switch to
the editor line tool
or the
shortcut key N.
After selecting
a set of lines,
right-click
and select
merge.
Now
this panel
will merge
into a complete
panel.
Now,
this panel
is a little narrow.
We can
make this panel
a little wider.
Next,
we will
repeat the
previous
operation.
So,
you can
watch the
video
and review it again.
Finally,
we can
untangle
the
butterfly
earplugs
and simulate
it together.
After watching
this tutorial video,
you can also
try to add some
butterfly decorations
on your
clothes.
This tutorial video ends here.
See you next time.
Bye bye.
Transcription by CastingWords